John R. Garman Papers
University of Houston-Clear Lake Archives & Special Collections
John R. Garman Papers
1967-1998
1970-1995
Garman, John R.
2013-0006
5.25 linear feet
University of Houston-Clear Lake Archives & Special Collections
John R. Garman Papers, 1967-1998 document John Garman's career at NASA, OAO Corporation, and the years after his retirement as software engineering and information technology consultant.
Biographical Sketch
John R. Garman was born in Oak Park, Illinois on September 11, 1944. He obtained a Bachelor of Science degree in Engineering Physics from the University of Michigan in 1966. That same year, Garman began working for the Johnson Space Center as Director of Flight Operations for the Mission Planning and Analysis Division of the Flight Support Division. He obtained progressively more responsible positions until he was appointed Deputy Director of the Mission Support Directorate in 1986. The following year, Garman went to Washington, D.C. as Director of Information Systems Services at the Space Station Program Office. On returning to the Johnson Space Center in 1988, Garman held a variety of positions, culminating in Chief Information Officer in 1994. He left NASA in 2000 and joined OAO Corporation in Greenbelt, Maryland. Lockheed Martin Information Technology of Seabrook, Maryland bought out OAO, and Garman became Technical Director, NASA Services for Lockheed Martin Information Technology. In 2010, Garman retired and became a consultant in software engineering and information technology. He is married to the former Susan Hallmark of Los Angeles, California and has two daughters.
Scope and Contents Note
The John R. Garman Papers include biographical information on Garman, documents on Apollo 11-16 missions and navigation systems, ALSA/SOMA programs and reports, programmed guidance equations and analysis, HAL compiler and language, STS avionics, the space station, Information Resource Management, photographs, and presentation slides.
Access Restrictions
Unrestricted
Index Terms
Subjects (Persons)
Garman, John R.
Subjects (Organizations)
Lyndon B. Johnson Space Center
Subjects
Project Apollo (U.S.); Space stations; Information resources management
Acquisition Information
Acquired from John R. Garman
Detailed Description of the Collection
- John R. Garman Papers, 1967-1998
  - John R. Garman Biographical Information, undated? (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Apollo Missions and Navigation Systems Characteristics, Jan. 17, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Apollo Missions and Navigation Systems Characteristics, Dec. 15, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Apollo 11-16 Memos, Aug. 4, 1969-May 10, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Apollo 11-16 Memos, Aug. 4, 1969-May 10, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Description of Apollo Guidance Analysis Statistical Trials Problem, Sept. 2, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - The Apollo 17 Task, Oct. 27, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - ALSA/SOMA Program Final Report Volume 1 and Volume1 and 2 CD, Jan. 1970-Jun. 1973 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - ALSA/SOMA Program Final Report Volume 1, Jan. 1970-Jun. 1973 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - ALSA/SOMA Program Final Report Volume 2, Jul. 1972-Jun.1973 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Viking 1977 and 1979 Performance Analysis, Jan. 27, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Programmed Guidance Equations for Colossus 3 Command Module, Earth Orbiter and Lunar Program Working Paper, Apr. 20, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Programmed Guidance Equations for Colossus 3 Command Module, Earth Orbiter and Lunar Program Working Paper, Apr. 20, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Programmed Guidance Equations for Colossus 3 Command Module, Earth Orbiter and Lunar Program Working Paper, Apr. 20, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - HAL Compiler and Language Specification Document, Jun. 1971 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - HAL Compiler and Language--Final Report, Volume 1: Development of an MSC Language and Compiler, Jun. 1971 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - HAL Compiler and Language--Final Report, Volume 2: A Guide to the HAL Programming Language, Jun. 1971 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Programmed Guidance Equations for Skylark Command Module, Earth Orbital Program, Folder 1/3, Feb. 14, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Programmed Guidance Equations for Skylark Command Module, Earth Orbital Program, Folder 2/3, Feb. 14, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Programmed Guidance Equations for Skylark Command Module, Earth Orbital Program, Folder 3/, Feb. 14, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Apollo Guidance and Navigation Control, Apr. 1972 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Requirements and Architecture of the Space Shuttle Flight Computer Operating System (FCOs) Intermetrics, Jul. 19, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Higher Order Software Requirements, Aug. 1973 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - STS Avionics--HAL/FCOS/SDL ICDS, circa 1974 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Principles of Higher Order Software Illustrated by Application to a Space Shuttle Prototype Program, Feb. 1974 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Design of the Software Executive Phase IIA Digital Fly-by-Wire Project Initial System, Mar. 1, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - GPC Software Structure Evaluation Team Report, Jul. 15, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - STS Avionics--HAL/S-FC PDR, HAL/S-C, Folder 1/3, Mar. 1974-Jul. 1975 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - STS Avionics--HAL/S-FC PDR, HAL/S-C, Folder 2/3, Mar. 1974-Jul. 1975 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - STS Avionics--HAL/S-FC PDR, HAL/S-C, Folder 3/3, Mar. 1974-Jul. 1975 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - AP-101 Linkage Editor Audit Report--Space Shuttle Orbiter Avionics Software, Feb. 13, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - HAL/S Programmer's Guide--Part 1, Jun. 11, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - HAL/S Programmer's Guide--Part 2, Jun. 11, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Higher Order Software, Inc.--Technical Report #5: The Manager as an Abstract Systems Engineer, Jun. 1977 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Programming in HAL/S, Sept. 1978 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Introduction to HAL/S, Oct. 1978 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Space Shuttle Program, Orbiter Project--Computer Development Specifications: Volume 1, Book 7, Nov. 27, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Space Shuttle-SPF Loading--IBM, Jun. 4, 1979-Jun. 13, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Analysis of Software Production Facility (SPF) Predicted Resource Requirements, Mar. 1980 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - HAL/S 360 User's Manual IR-360-2, May 1, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - HAL/S Language Specification Version IR-542, Folder 1/2, Sept. 1980 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - HAL/S Language Specification Version IR-542, Folder 2/2, Sept. 1980 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - STS-1 Technical Crew Debriefing, Apr. 1981 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - STS-1 Orbiter Mission Report, Jun. 1981 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - HAL/S Flight Computer User's Manual, circa 1981 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - The Bug Heard Round the World--Discussions of the Software Problem That Delayed the First Shuttle Orbital Flight by John R. Garman, Deputy Chief, Spacecraft Software Division, 1981; 1983 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Space Transportation and Ground Control Systems: The IBM Role, Jun. 1982 (Box 7, Folder 6)